# **Naveed Ahmed**

💌 naveed49478@gmail.com 📞 +923310049478 in LinkedIn 🔭 Portfolio 🕥 GitHub 🖸 YouTube

# **PROFILE**

As a Python Data Scientist & ML Engineer, I have spent 4+ years immersing myself in ML & DS. With my background in DL, Mathematics and Statistics, ML, DS, and some research experience I would be a strong candidate for the Ms/Ph.D. position.

#### **AWARDS**

Gold Medalist (BSCS), University of Gujrat

Got a fully funded scholarship (BSCS), Higher Education Commission, Pakistan

Won Grant for the project "Autonomous Car Using Raspberry PI", NGIRI (ICT Funding) by Ignite - NTF

Azure Data Scientist Associate, Microsoft Certified

Presented Research Paper in 11th International Conference (ROVISP)

#### SKILLS

AI Technology

Python | Machine Learning | Deep Learning | Linear Algebra | Calculus | Probability | Statistics | NLP | Azure | AWS | GCP | TensorFlow, Keras, Pytorch | Chatbots | Flask/Django | Docker | Kubernetes | Data Science | SQL | Git | Latex | Scikit | Recommendation & Prediction Systems

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Calrom (UK company)

**Principal Data Scientist** 08/2022 - present

- Designed and built different prediction systems including a smart flight recommendation system using ML/DL algorithms, AzureML pipelines, python, SQL, Flask, Docker, and Git from which the company saves 60-90£ against each passenger.

Senior Data Scientist 07/2021 - 08/2022

Built MRO application for medical using NLP, Azure Form Recognizer, Google Machine Vision, AWS boto3, Docker, Kubernetes, Django, and SQL.

Dealers Gear (US company) 09/2020 - 07/2021

Data scientist

Built chatbots using SOTA, a recommendation system for cars, Google Ads Management Robot, and built different NLP-based web apps including Marketing using NLP using GPT3, BERT,

## University of Gujrat, Pakistan

**Teacher Assistant** 09/2020 - 03/2021

- Conduct programming labs of Python/C++ and work with different professors.

ML Research Assistant 03/2019 - 09/2020

- Worked on different projects with the collaboration of different professors using different architectures including RNN, LSTM, BILSTM, Transformers, and Machine Translation using Pretrained models like T5 and GPT, writing research papers in Latex, and research publications.

Minds Work, Pakistan 03/2018 - 09/2018

Software developer

- Develop websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, jQuery, PHP and C#

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

"Handling Illusive Text in Document to Improve Accuracy of Plagiarism Detection Algorithm The 11th International Conference on Robotics, Vision, Signal Processing, and Power Applications (RoViSP) 2021

Effective Solution of University Course Timetabling using Particle Swarm Optimizer based Hyper Heuristic approach **Baghdad Science Journal** 

# CERTIFICATES

- Python for Data Science, AI

& Development (IBM)

- AI For Everyone (deeplearning.ai) - Deep Learning Specialization (deeplearning.ai)

- Azure Data Scientist Associate, Microsoft Certified

# **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Computer Science (BSCS)** University of Gujrat CGPA: 3.72/4.0 with distinction Gold Medalist